

# CRISTIAN IONUT TOPORASCU

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

### ABOUT ME

A multi-disciplinary designer / developer with a balance of creative and technical skills. I specialise in interaction and interface design, and front-end development.

Taking projects from requirements gathering, through wireframing and prototyping, to completed build.

Familiarised with a wide-range of development and design tools, being able to work within a full-stack front-end and back-end development role with an exemplary attention to details.

# > CONTACT ME

- +44 7826 151 155
- toporascu.cristian@gmail.com
- 2 12 The Green Field Coventry, West Midlands, CV3 1EE

# **>** FOLLOW

- facebook.com/toporascu.ionut
- in linkedin.com/in/cristian-ionut
- cristiantoporascu.github.io

### **INTERESTS**









### WORK EXPERIENCE

# + ENCORSA FREE LANCING SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

2019 - Present

My role during the contracts I finished working for ENCORSA constisted of:

- Developed tools and applications using Native Android development as well as Unity for the applications that required a more fluid UI and faster development.
- Built API's and Web Applications using .NET Framework which very often they they included functionality for login or custom CMS using Entity and Identity framework.
- Maintained and Supported other developers if requested by the client.

### + VITSOE LTD.

2018 - Present

### JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER

My role at Vitsoe constisted of:

- Working in a small focused team towards maintaining the current custom CMS and ERP systems, as well as adding additional futures if required in order for our production team to be able to produce the best product for our customers.
- Developing new concepts and working with the team on creating web tools for furniture design that would allow our customers to get the best experience of buying our products.
- Monitoring and researching the user behaviour and evolving designs of how the UX and UI of the customer areas of the website could be improved

#### + FREE LANCING

2017 - 2018

#### 3D VISUALISATION

During the time spent at the University, I got the opportunity to also work and create 3D Visualtisations of my customers' houses as they wanted to redecorate.

My main tasks were usualy:

- Meeting up with the customers and making up the criterias of the product they want.
- Getting and understanding of the house's blueprint and building the actual visualisation project using 3DSMax.
- Putting up ideas for the house design both interior and exterior according with the customer's needs.

# SKILLS

### Main skill set:

- HTML5 / CSS 3
- JAVASCRIPT / JQUERY
- REACT JS / VUE JS
- C++ / C# / OOP
- RESPONSIVE DESIGN
- SASS / SCSS
- GAMES ARHITECTURE
- ALGORITHMS

### **EDUCATION**

#### + COVENTRY UNIVERSITY

2016 - Present

GAMES TECHNOLOGY- 1ST HR

During my Games Technology course, I learned a lot about the way the global games industry is evolving, as well as how can take advantage of all the tools and current developed video games, in order to develop myself as a game developer and get the necesarry experience to become a games programmer.